Guide to the Radio Bandung Collection TAM.746
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Radio Bandung Collection
1986-1998
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Radio Bandung
TAM.746
2 linear feet in 1 record carton and 2 manuscript boxes
Radio Bandung was a weekly radio newsmagazine from 1991 through the late 1990s that aimed to deliver news and cultural information about Asian/Pacific/American communities and the Asian/Pacific geographic region to the general public. Domestic topics covered on the program included anti-immigration hearings, South Asian taxi drivers in New York City, the Native Hawaiian independence movement, and LGBTQ rights. International issues included AIDS activism in Southeast Asia, new film movements in China and Vietnam, and redress efforts over the forced sexual slavery of Korean women and girls by the Imperial Japanese Army before and during World War II (euphemistically referred to as "comfort women"). The Radio Bandung Collection (dated 1986-1998) consists of materials documenting the program's regular activities, including typed and handwritten logs for individual programs, including show outlines, edit scripts, names of specific guests, and topics discussed; grant applications, grant progress reports, and other financial records; and materials related to Radio Bandung's workshop series to teach media skills to community members, including session outlines, equipment sign-out sheets, and technical manuals for radio production equipment. The collection also includes materials concerning the production of the documentary Silent Decades: Chinatown and McCarthyism, including press kits, drafts and transcripts in various stages, and editing documents. The collection documents the specific Radio Bandung program, as well as Asian/Pacific/American experiences concerning racism, discrimination, immigration, and ethnic identity. The collection demonstrates an effort from within the Asian/Pacific/American community to represent and analyze these community experiences.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred to Tamiment Library in April 2018. The accession number associated with this transfer is 2018.048.
Arrangement
This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. Original order is unknown.
Historical Note
Radio Bandung was a New York City-based weekly radio newsmagazine from 1991 through the late 1990s devoted to news and cultural information about Asian/Pacific/American communities and the Asian/Pacific geographic region to the general public. Radio Bandung began as a volunteer-operated project of Women's International Film and was broadcast in New York on WBAI/Pacifica Radio 99.5 FM. Domestic topics covered on the program included anti-immigration hearings, South Asian taxi drivers in New York City, the Native Hawaiian independence movement, and LGBTQ rights. International issues included AIDS activism in Southeast Asia, new film movements in China and Vietnam, and redress efforts over the forced sexual slavery of Korean women and girls by the Imperial Japanese Army before and during World War II (euphemistically referred to as "comfort women"). Radio Bandung also offered training workshops in audio production intended to develop production and hosting skills for interested community members.
Custodial History
Tamiment Library has no information concerning the provenance of this collection. The collection was previously housed at the Fales Library and Special Collections, until it was deaccessioned and transferred to Tamiment in April 2018 due to its unknown provenance and the absence of a contract.
Scope and Contents
The Radio Bandung Collection (dated 1986-1998) consists of materials documenting Radio Bandung, a weekly Asian/Pacific/American radio newsmagazine broadcast over WBAI 99.5 FM. Materials in this collection include typed and handwritten logs documenting the individual programs, including show outlines, edit scripts, names of specific guests, and topics discussed; grant applications, grant progress reports, and other financial records; and materials related to Radio Bandung's workshop series to teach media skills to community members, including session outlines, equipment sign-out sheets, and technical manuals for radio production equipment. The collection also includes materials concerning the production of the documentary Silent Decades: Chinatown and McCarthyism, including press kits, drafts and transcripts in various stages, and editing documents. The collection documents the specific Radio Bandung program, as well as Asian/Pacific/American experiences concerning racism, discrimination, immigration, and ethnic identity. The collection demonstrates an effort from within the Asian/Pacific/American community to represent and analyze these community experiences.
Alternative mass media.; Asian American mass media; Mass media and culture.; Mass media -- Political aspects -- United States.; Pacific Islander Americans; Asian Americans.; Asian Americans -- Ethnic identity.; Asian Americans -- Race identity; WBAI Radio (New York, N.Y.)
- Radio Equipment, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Ephemera, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Museum of Chinese in the Americas, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Handwritten and Duplicate Logs, 1986-1990 (Box 1, Folder 4-5)
- Typed Logs, circa 1980s-1990s (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Edit Scripts (Old), circa 1980s-1990s (Box 1, Folder 7-8)
- Funding Organization Reports, 1992-1996 (Box 1, Folder 9-12)
- Accounts Payable, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 13-14)
- Silent Decades: General, circa 1980s-1990s (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Silent Decades: Rough and Paper Cuts, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 16-17)
- Grant Applications, 1990s (Box 1, Folder 18-19)
- Accounts Receivable, 1990s (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Asian American Arts Alliance Technical Assistance and Regrant Initiative, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- PrimaLux Video, circa 1990s (Box 1, Folder 22)
- TARI and NorthStar Fund, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Peace Development Fund, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Paul Robeson Fund, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Fox Lorber, circa 1990s (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Budgets, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Silent Decades: Synopsis, circa 1990s (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Grants, 1994-1996 (Box 1, Folder 29-32)
- Materials for the Arts, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Corporation for Public Broadcasting, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Silent Decades: Editing, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Minutes: Fundraising, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Minutes: Coordinating, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Applications and Fax Cover Sheets, circa 1980s-1990s (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Silent Decades: Paper Cut and Notes, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 39-40)
- Minutes: General Meeting, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 41)
- Silent Decades: Home Movies Appeal, undated (Box 1, Folder 42)
- Logs, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Index Cards, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- WBAI Pacifica Notes, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Postal Rates, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Financial Records, 1996-1997 (Box 2, Folder 5-6)
- Accounts Payable, 1995-1996 (Box 2, Folder 7-8)
- Silent Decades: Correspondence, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Newspaper on Philanthropy, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Notebook, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Media Arts Program Proposal, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Workshop Expenses, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Production Workshop, circa 1980s-1990 (Box 2, Folder 14-15)
- Notes, circa 1980s-1990 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Production Workshop Agreement, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Resumes, circa 1980s-1990s (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Equipment Checkout, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Workshop, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 4-5)
- Asia Society, 1990-1994 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Proposal Rough Drafts, circa 1980s-1990s (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Radio Bandung Stamp, circa 1980s-1990s (Box 3)